Guide to the Richard Bruce Nugent Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Poems, short works of fiction and nonfiction, interviews, 1920s-1985; Series II; (10 boxes)
  - Notes and Outlines, Several Leaves (Box 27)
  - Holograph Fragments, Numerous Leaves (Box 27)
  - Holograph Fragments, Numerous Leaves (Box 27)
  - Typed Fragments, Numerous Leaves (Box 27)
  - Harlem: A Cultural Capitol--Holograph Notes, 5 Leaves (Box 27)
  - Greek Language Notes, 7 Leaves (Box 27)
  - Autobiography of Me, ca 15 Leaves (Box 27)
    Author unknown (probably not Nugent)
  - Philosophy, 4 Leaves (Box 27)
- Long works of fiction, novels, 1929-1985; Series III; (18 boxes)
  - CIAO, ca 1970-1985 (Box 28)
    There are three, or perhaps four, typed drafts of CIAO. They are labeled I-III, with Draft I being the latest and Draft III the earliest. While there are gaps, it appears that a nearly complete manuscript can be pieced together.
  - CIAO. Last Draft (I). Pages 1-147, ca 1970-1985; 150 leaves. Ribbon typescript with occasional holograph corrections. (Box 28)
  - CIAO. Last Draft(I), pp. 148-243+; 235-243*, ca 1975-1985; ca 106 leaves. Ribbon typescript with occasional holograph corrections. (Box 28)
    Urine stains * It is unclear where this group of pages belongs. The pagination duplicates the last draft typescript, but the contents do not.
  - CIAO. "After the Wedding." Later Draft(II). Unpaginated, ca 1975-1985; 13 leaves. Typescript with numerous holograph corrections. (Box 28)
  - CIAO. "Borghese Gardens." Last Draft (I). Unpaginated., ca 1975-1985; 11 leaves. Ribbon typescript with occasional holograph corrections. (Box 28)
  - CIAO. "Cas'Amici." Early Draft (III). Unpaginated., ca 1975-1985; 3 leaves. Ribbon typescript with occasional holograph corrections. (Box 28)
  - CIAO. "Salvatore" Early Draft (III), pp. 1-7, ca 1975-1985; 7 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28)
    Urine stains & residue
  - CIAO. "Completion of Cas'Amici" Early Draft (III), pp 1-12. Incomplete., ca 1975-1985; 12 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28)
  - CIAO: "Sarah (After Alberto)" Early Draft (III)., ca 1975-1985; 3 Leaves. Ribbon Typescript with a few holograph corrections. (Box 28)
  - CIAO. "Alfredo after the day the house is finished" Early Draft (III). Unpaginated, ca 1975-1985; 11 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28)
  - CIAO. "Tania's Death" Early Draft (III), pp. 1-9, with passages about Sarah before and after., ca 1975-1985; 11 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "Venice" Early Draft (III). Unpaginated., ca 1975-1985; 20 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "Return from Venice" Early Draft (III), pp. 1-5., ca 1975-1985; 5 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "Gianni Arrives (After Venice)" Later Draft (II), pp. 1-10., ca 1975-1985; 10 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "Marco & Franco after Tania's Death" Early Draft (III), pp. 1-13., ca 1975-1985; 13 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "Women's Dinner" Last Draft (I), pp. 1-16; Early Draft (III), pp. 1-16., ca 1975-1985; 33 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "Jean-Claude Meeting Renaldo" Early Draft (III), pp. 1-10., ca 1975-1985; 10 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "Gathering: The Men's Dinner". Early Draft (III), pp. 1-24., ca 1975-1985; 25 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "Dario & Jean-Claude after the Men's Dinner". Early Draft (III). Unpaginated., ca 1975-1985; 30 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "Sarah, Dario & Dorea" Last Draft (I), pp. 1-9., ca 1975-1985; 9 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "Meeting Ibn". Last Draft (I). Partly Unpaginated., ca 1975-1985; 59 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "After Ibn--with Dario". Last Draft (I), pp. 1-80., ca 1975-1985; 82 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29)
  - CIAO. "The Dispersal--Reading the Will" Various Drafts. Unpaginated., ca 1975-1985; 17 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 30)
    Incomplete.
  - CIAO. "The Dispersal--Saul, Sarah, Jean-Claude" Early Draft (III), pp. 1-11 & Unpaginated, ca 1975-1985; 12 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 30)
  - CIAO. "Gianni's Garden--The Last Gathering". Later Draft (II), unpaginated., 6 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 30)
  - CIAO. "The Dispersal--Sarah & Cecco" Early Draft (III), pp. 1-16, ca 1975-1985; 17 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 30)
  - CIAO. "The Dispersal--Sarah the Morning AFter" Early Draft (III), pp. a-f., ca 1975-1985; 7 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 30)
  - CIAO. "Greece; Hijack" Early Draft (III), pp. a-e; Last Draft (I), pp. 56+; 58-67; & unpaginated., ca 1975-1985; 21 leaves. Ribbon typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 30)
  - CIAO. "Doxology" (Last Chapter) Last Draft (I), pp. 1-3; Later Draft (II), Unpaginated, ca 1975-1985; 39 leaves. Ribbon & carbon typescripts with holograph corrections. (Box 30)
    Draft I is incomplete, consisting of only pp. 1-3. Draft II is present in two versions: a ribbon copy of pp. 3-18 and a carbon copy of pp. 1-18 (pagination supplied).
  - CIAO. Later Draft (II), pp. 1-180, ca 1975-1985; ca 184 leaves. Ribbon typescript with a occasional holograph corrections. (Box 30)
    No missing pages, but incomplete.
  - CIAO. Later Draft (II), pp. 1-63, ca 1975-1985; 65 leaves. Carbon typescript with a occasional holograph corrections. (Box 30)
  - CIAO. Later Draft (II), pp. 1-180, ca 1975-1985; ca 184 leaves. Xerox copy of the ribbon with a few holograph corrections. (Box 31)
  - CIAO. "Early Draft (III), pp. 1-22, ca 1975-1985; 27 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 31)
    Corresponds with pp. 1-39 of Draft I
  - CIAO. "The Journal--First Trip" Early Draft (III), pp. 23-79, ca 1975-1985; ca. 57 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 31)
    Corresponds with pp. 40-115 of Draft I.
  - CIAO. "The Journal--Second Trip" Early Draft (III), pp. 83-101, ca 1975-1985; ca. 20 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 31)
    Corresponds to pp. 116-147 of Craft I
  - CIAO. "The Journal--Third Trip" Early Draft (III),Unaginated & pp. 1-17, 22-24, 26., ca 1975-1985; ca. 24 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 31)
    Corresponds to Draft I, pp. 148-183.
  - CIAO. Early Draft(s?) (III), Various pages., ca 1975-1985; ca. 17 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 31)
    Corresponds to Draft I, pp. 175-178; 181-184; 189-200; 202-203.
  - CIAO. Early Draft(s?) (III), Various pages., ca 1975-1985; ca. 27 leaves. Ribbon & carbon copies with holograph corrections. (Box 31)
    Corresponds to Draft I, pp. 212-229
  - CIAO. Early Draft(s?) (III), Various pages., ca 1975-1985; ca. 32 leaves. Ribbon & carbon copies with holograph corrections. (Box 32)
    Corresponds to Draft I, pp. 229-243.
  - CIAO. "Borghese Gardens" Early Draft (III), pp. a-i, ca 1975-1985; ca. 11 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 32)
  - CIAO. "Men's Dinner". Early Drafts (III), pp. 5-8; 7-15; Unpaginated, ca 1975-1985; ca. 14 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 32)
  - CIAO. "Meeting Ibn". Early Draft (III), pp. 1-7; 15, ca 1975-1985; ca. 9 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 32)
  - CIAO. "After Ibn". Early Draft (III), pp. 1-12; 14-52, ca 1975-1985; ca. 52 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 32)
  - CIAO. Unsorted Typescript Pages, ca 1975-1985; ca. 27 leaves. Ribbon copies with holograph corrections. (Box 32)
  - CIAO. Holograph & Typed Fragments, ca 1975-1985; Numerous leaves (Box 32)
  - CIAO. Holograph Notes, ca 1975-1985; 1 Leaf. (Box 32)
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER (Box 33)
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft I, pp. 1-7; 12-36, 33 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 3-9; 12; 19-40.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft I, Unpaginated, 8 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. Tanned, acidic paper. Each leaf in a protective polyester folder. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 46-55
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft I, Unpaginated, 11 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 56-65.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft I, Unpaginated, 8 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 81-87.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft I, Unpaginated, 6 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 88-92.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft I, pp. I-VI, 6 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 107-112.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft I, Unpaginated, 2 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 117-118.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft I, Unpaginated, 2 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 149-150.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft I, Unpaginated, 9 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 308-316.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft I, Unpaginated, 4 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 317-320.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. "Dear Bum:" Draft I, Unpaginated, 5 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Omitted from the published version
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft II, pp. 7-10, 4 leaves. Typed, carbon copy. Acidic, tanned paper in polyester folders. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 8-11.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft II, pp. 4; 8-13; 18-19, 9 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. Acidic, tanned paper in polyester folders. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 64-69.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. "Picnic" Draft II, pp. 1-5., 5 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. Yellow-orange paper in polyester folders. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 130-134.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. "Picnic" Draft II (?), pp. 26-31., 6 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. Acidic, tanned paper in polyester folders. Edges chipped. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 134-139.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft II, pp. 14-20, 7 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. Acidic, tanned paper in polyester folders. Edges chipped. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 150-157.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft II, pp. a-b., 2 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. Acidic, tanned paper in polyester folders. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 307-309.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft III, p. 4., 1 leaf. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Corresponds to the published version, p. 56.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft III, pp. 1-3., 3 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. Acidic, tanned paper in polyester folders. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 71-74
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft III, Unpaginated., 24 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 171-189.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft III, Unpaginated., 15 leaves. Typed, ribbon copy. (Box 33)
    Published version, pp. 292-305.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, pp. 1-6., 6 leaves. Holograph. (Box 34)
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, pp. 3-8., 6 leaves. Holograph on tanned, acidic & fragile paper. Chipped. Protected with polyester folders. (Box 34)
    Published version, pp. 92-101.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV., 1 leaf. Holograph. Top half of the page missing. Protected with a polyester folder. (Box 34)
    Published version, p. 189.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, "Chapter 3", pp. 1-20, 20 leaves. Holograph. Some pages chipped and/or stained. Leaves protected with polyester folders. (Box 34)
    Published version, pp. 189-208.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, "Chapter 4, Second Part", Unpaginated, 6 leaves. Holograph on tanned, acidic, disintegrating paper. Badly chipped, affecting the text. Leaves protected with polyester folders. (Box 34)
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, "Chapter on Meeting Orini" ff, pp. 1-14, 17; pp. 1-7; pp. 1-6, 30 leaves. Holograph. Leaves protected with polyester folders. (Box 34)
    Published version, pp. 218-258.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, pp. 1-12, 12 leaves. Holograph. (Box 34)
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. "After Orini (After the Ball". Draft IV, pp. 1-10, 10 leaves. Holograph on tanned, acidic paper. Protected with polyester folders. (Box 34)
    Published version, pp. 279-291.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, pp. 14-15, 2 leaves. Holograph on tanned, acidic paper. Protected with polyester folders. (Box 34)
    Published version, pp. 305-306.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, p. 5, 1 leaves. Holograph. Protected with a polyester folder. (Box 34)
    Corresponds to the published version, pp. 307-308.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, pp. 5-14., 10 leaves. Holograph. (Box 34)
    Published version, pp. 320-327.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, pp. 1-6., 6 leaves. Holograph. (Box 34)
    Published version, pp. 327-331.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, pp. 1-3, 7., 4 leaves. Holograph on tanned, acidic paper. Chipped. Protected with polyester folders. (Box 34)
    Omitted from the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft IV, Unpaginated, 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 34)
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft V, pp. 2-16, 15 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 34)
    Corresponds to pp. 4-12; 19-21 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft V, pp. 1-15; 17-18, 17 leaves. Carbon copy. (Box 34)
    Corresponds to pp. 3-12; 19-20; 21-24 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VI, pp. 3-[4], 2 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 34)
    Corresponds to pp. 10-12 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VI, Unpaginated, 2 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 34)
    Pp. 27-32 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VI, Unpaginated, 3 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 34)
    Pp. 40-42 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VI, "Last Chapter", pp.1-5, 5 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 34)
    Pp. 165-168 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. (Box 35)
    Box 3-8 is oversize (legal)
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VII. Unpaginated, ca. 1930; 2 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 35)
    Corresponds to p. 19 of the published version, together with some material omitted from the published version. Draft VII contains the real-life names of the characters, crossed out with the fictional names substituted.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VII. pp. 1-2., ca. 1930; 2 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 35)
    Corresponds to pp. 20-23 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VII. "New Part" pp. 1-7., ca. 1930; 7 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 35)
    Pp. 74-80 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VII, p. 4., ca. 1930; 1 partial leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 35)
    Published version,, p. 116
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VII. pp. 7-12., ca. 1930; 6 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 35)
    Pp. 118-123 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VII. pp. 1-3, ca. 1930; 3 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 35)
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VII. Unpaginated, ca. 1930; 1 leaf. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 35)
    Pp. 162-163 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VII. Unpaginated, ca. 1930; 1 partial leaves and 1 full leaf. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections. (Box 35)
    Odd pages
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VIII, pp. 13-16, ca. 1929; 4 leaves. Holograph copy with corrections. (Box 35)
    Pp. 42-45 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VIII, Unpaginated, ca. 1929; 1 leaf. Holograph copy with corrections. (Box 35)
    Single paragraph insert. Corresponds to pp. 71-72 in the published version..
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VIII, pp. 9-27, ca. 1929; 15 leaves. Holograph copy with corrections. Recto & verso. (Box 35)
    Alternate versions labeled pp. 10-12 & unpaginated crossed out on some versos. Pp. 103-107, 112-115 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VIII, pp. 1-10, ca. 1929; 10 leaves. Holograph copy with corrections. (Box 35)
    Pp. 123-129 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VIII,"New Part", pp. 1-12, ca. 1929; 10 leaves. Holograph copy with corrections. Paper tanned & somewhat fragile. Protected with polyester folders (Box 35)
    Pp. 140-149 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VIII, pp. 2-3, ca. 1929; 2 leaves. Holograph copy with corrections. (Box 35)
    Pp. 161-162 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VIII, pp. 1-3, ca. 1929; 3 leaves. Holograph copy with corrections (1 typed paragraph). Paper tanned & somewhat fragile. Protected with polyester folders (Box 35)
    Pp. 163-165 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VIII, pp. 1-3, ca. 1929; 3 leaves. Holograph copy with corrections. Paper tanned & somewhat fragile. Protected with polyester folders. (Box 35)
    Not included in the final text.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VIII, Unpaginated, ca. 1929; 1 leaf. Holograph copy with corrections. Paper stained. Top of the page torn off, apparently not affecting any text. (Box 35)
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Fragments, ca. 1929; 4 leaves. (Box 35)
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Wallace Thurman Biographical Notes, ca. 1929; 1 leaf. (Box 35)
    Large chips, not affecting the text.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft VIII, "New Part" [Thurman's Family in Salt Lake City], pp. 1-9., ca. 1929; 9 legal-size leaves. Holograph, pencil with corrections in ink. (Box 35)
    Pp. 13-18 of the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. Draft II (?), pp. 10-13. [Myra & Aeon], 5 legal-size leaves. Ribbon copy, with a carbon of p. 13 (Box 35)
    Not included in the published version.
  - GENTLEMAN JIGGER. [Burton Brascoe's Wedding], ca 1929; 2 legal-size leaves. Holograph (in pencil) on tanned, stained paper. First leaf chipped at the bottom, affecting the text. (Box 35)
    Ends abruptly; probably incomplete. Burton Brascoe was actually Countee Cullen.
  - THE SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE, 1970S-1980S (Box 36)
    This novel is incomplete, and the order of chapters is not entirely clear.
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Last Draft, pp. 1-99, 1970s-1980s; ca. 100 leaves (Box 36)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Last Draft, pp. 100-267, 1970s-1980s; ca. 166 leaves. (Box 36)
    Missing p. 234. Incomplete.
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Early Draft, pp. 1-28, 1970s-1980s; ca. 29 leaves. With numerous corrections by Nugent (Box 37)
    Corresponds to pp. 1-39 of the Last Draft.
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Early Draft, pp. 29-48, 1970s-1980s; ca 21 leaves (Box 37)
    Corresponds to pp. 40-72 of the Last Draft.
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Early Draft, pp. 48(?),49-127, 1970s-1980s; ca. 80 leaves (Box 37)
    Corresponds to pp. 73-170 of the Last Draft.
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Early Draft, pp. 129-158, 1970s-1980s; ca. 27 leaves (Box 37)
    Corresponds to pp. 171- 210 of the Last Draft. Many pages missing or torn, page numbers confused. All but one leaf are copies of malodorous originals filed in Series 16. The cats used these papers as a litter box).
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Early Draft, pp. 159-173, 175, 180, 1970s-1980s (Box 37)
    Corresponds to pp. 211-228 of the Last Draft.
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Early Draft, pp. 1-6, a-z, 1970s-1980s; ca 30 leaves (Box 37)
    Corresponds to pp. 229-276 of the Last Draft.
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Rom (After Jail & Prettyboy), 1970s-1980s; 9 leaves + 2 leaves (Box 37)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. [Louise, Eddy, Freddie, Franikie, Jimmie], 1970s-1980s; ca. 45 leaves (Box 37)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Rome, before Naples. Meeting Iolas, 1970s-1980s; 37 leaves. Many holograph & typed corrections (Box 38)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Rome to Naples., 1970s-1980s; ca 53 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 38)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Naples. Giovanni, Aldo, Adriano, Fredo, 1970s-1980s; ca 36 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 38)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Naples. Night with Annibale (Fauno); Reunion with Danni, 1970s-1980s; ca 28 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 38)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Calabria with Danni. Irene, Gordo Giordano, 1970s-1980s; 5 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 38)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Naples. Danni, Cadmo, Cristosms, Dimitrius, 1970s-1980s; 16 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 38)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Naples. Annibale, after Danni, 1970s-1980s; 14 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 38)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Naples. Cadmo, Eugenio, 1970s-1980s; 22 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 38)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Naples. Leaves Annibale. Iolas, Cristosmos, Ernesto, Igor, 1970s-1980s; ca 23 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 38)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Naples. Last Night. Dom. Departure for Ischia, 1970s-1980s; ca 34 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 38)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Ischia. Arrival, 1970s-1980s; 42 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 39)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Ischia. Iolas Arrives. Costas, 1970s-1980s; 52 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 39)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Ischia. Costas, Castor, Iolas, 1970s-1980s; 38 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 39)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Ischia. Costas' Dinner, 1970s-1980s; 14 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 39)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Ischia. Iolas Returns after Costas' Dinner, 1970s-1980s; 21 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 39)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Ischia. Last Day., 1970s-1980s; 23 leaves. Many holograph corrections (Box 39)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (Italy). Rome after Ischia., 1970s-1980s; 7 leaves. Holograph corrections (Box 39)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Recounting to Ruben., 1970s-1980s; 7 leaves. Holograph corrections (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Aeon Meets Eva, 1970s-1980s; 3 leaves. Typescript & holograph notes (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Yannis, 1970s-1980s; 13 leaves. (pp.131-144) Many holograph notes (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Charles, Andrea, Redwing, 1970s-1980s; 50 leaves. (pp.146-195) Many holograph notes (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Eva Pregnant, 1970s-1980s; 2 leaves. (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). After Eva Moves In, 1970s-1980s; 4 leaves. (Box 40)
    Incomplete
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Giacomo (James), 1970s-1980s; 4 leaves (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Charles, after Fiore & Miele, 1970s-1980s; 7 leaves. (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Ruben, before the Love Tape, 1970s-1980s; 6 leaves. (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Tape from Iolas; Redwing, 1970s-1980s; 33 leaves. (Box 40)
    Many holograph corrections.
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Rom, after Iolas Tape, 1970s-1980s; 6 leaves. (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE (New York). Leaving the Firehouse, 1970s-1980s; 3 leaves. (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Odd Typescript Pages, 1970s-1980s; ca 30 leaves. (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Copies of Unsorted Malodorous Material, 1970s-1980s; ca 20 leaves. (Box 40)
  - SQUARE OF THE CIRCLE. Notes & Fragments, 1970s-1980s; ca 40 leaves. (Box 40)
  - THIS IS THE DAY, ca 1970s (Box 41)
    This manuscript is incomplete in many places, and the order in which the various sections belong is not entirely clear.
  - THIS IS THE DAY. "Oberon & Danny/Danny & Oberon," pp. 1-6; G(7)-I (9); L, M+, ca 1970s; 12 leaves. Ribbon copy with holograph corrections on the verso of "The Polyglot Company" letterhead (Box 41)
    The Polyglot Company was Bernard Kay's translation service.